<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Code on BrickSim</title><link>https://BrickSim.org/docs/contributing/code/</link><description>Recent content in Code on BrickSim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://BrickSim.org/docs/contributing/code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Workspace Setup</title><link>https://BrickSim.org/docs/contributing/code/workspace_setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://BrickSim.org/docs/contributing/code/workspace_setup/</guid><description>This page describes how to set up your workspace, so you can develop on BrickSim too.
Preparation on Windows Download MSYS2 from https://www.msys2.org/ and follow the installation instructions there. Execute the following command in a MSYS2 Shell to install git: pacman -S git Preparation on MacOS Execute the following command to install the XCode command line tools if you haven't already: sudo xcode-select --install Preparation on Linux Execute the following command to install git sudo apt install git Setup the workspace Do the platform-specific preparation Clone the repository by git clone --recurse-submodules -j8 https://github.</description></item><item><title>Using VS Code on Windows</title><link>https://BrickSim.org/docs/contributing/code/vscode_setup_windows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://BrickSim.org/docs/contributing/code/vscode_setup_windows/</guid><description>add C:\msys64\mingw64\bin to PATH Download and install VS Code from here if you haven't already Install the extensions ms-vscode.cpptools and ms-vscode.cmake-tools Open the BrickSim folder in VS Code. you should get the notifications like in the following screenshot (at least the first one):
click &amp;quot;yes&amp;quot; on the first notification, we'll deal with the second one later. Now it's time to adjust some settings: Press Ctrl + Shift+ P and type &amp;quot;preferences: Open Settings (JSON)&amp;quot;</description></item><item><title>Using VS Code on Linux</title><link>https://BrickSim.org/docs/contributing/code/vscode_setup_linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://BrickSim.org/docs/contributing/code/vscode_setup_linux/</guid><description>This tutorial was tested on Ubuntu 20.10, but it should work too on other versions or distributions. You'll have to install packages manually if you don't have apt.
Do all steps from here Install VS Code via a way described in the offical VS Code docs Open VS Code and install the ms-vscode.cpptools and ms-vscode.cmake-tools extensions Press Ctrl + Shift+ P and type &amp;quot;preferences: Open Settings (JSON)&amp;quot;
Hit Enter or click the first result and add the following text: 1 2 3 4 5 6 { &amp;#34;cmake.</description></item></channel></rss>