<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>BrickSim</title><link>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/</link><description>Recent content on BrickSim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 10:44:27 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Planned Features</title><link>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/features/_planned/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/features/_planned/</guid><description>The following table lists all bigger features which are planned but not realized yet. Feel free to vote for them on their GitHub Issue.
Description GitHub Issue Display a transform gizmo to translate and rotate things directly inside the 3D view #2 Save the model back to a .ldr or .mpd file #3 Pan function in 3D view #4 Customizable line thickness #5 Set camera origin to part location #7 Static analysis (just here for completeness, there's a separate page for this Milestone #1</description></item><item><title>Technologies and dependencies</title><link>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/technical_info/technologies_dependencies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/technical_info/technologies_dependencies/</guid><description>Logo Description BrickSim uses C++. The main reason for this choice was execution speed. BrickSim is built using the platform-independent build system CMake. The User Interface is made with Dear ImGui. OpenGL is used for rendering on all platforms. SQLite3 is used to save settings and cache to the disk. The library SQLiteCpp is used.</description></item><item><title>Windows</title><link>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/installation/windows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/installation/windows/</guid><description>currently, the only way to run BrickSim on Windows is to build it from source. A .exe file will be provided as soon as I have figured out how to build it in GitHub Actions on Windows.</description></item><item><title>Code</title><link>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/contributing/code/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/contributing/code/</guid><description>If you want to contribute to the code, you should know the following things:
How git and GitHub works How to code in C++ How Dear ImGui works (The Demo is included in BrickSim, the best way for me was to play around and then Ctrl+F for a display text to quickly navigate to the corresponding code lines) If you don't know one of the technologies yet, there are many tutorials on the internet.</description></item><item><title>Code structure</title><link>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/technical_info/code_structure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/technical_info/code_structure/</guid><description>All source files are located in the src/ Subfolder. The src/lib/ folder is for all third-party code.
Files Purpose Description main.cpp Starter This file is the entry point and just creates the controller. controller.h controller.cpp Controller The controller controls the program flow. shaders/* Shaders This folder contains a Shader class which is used to load shaders and modify their state.</description></item><item><title>Linux</title><link>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/installation/linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/installation/linux/</guid><description> Go to CMake Linux Build, select the topmost run and download the &amp;quot;BrickSimLinux&amp;quot; artifact. Unzip it somewhere Open the terminal and go to the folder you unzipped the files Mark the program as executable with the following command: chmod a+x BrickSim Install some dependencies: sudo apt install libgl1-mesa-dev libglew-dev Run the program with ./BrickSim</description></item><item><title>Static Analysis</title><link>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/features/static_analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/features/static_analysis/</guid><description>Vision Imagine designing a large bridge with LEGO(R) parts. Wouldn't it be useful if you could see whether your construction is robust before you order the parts? Depending on that, you might even find a better solution that is stronger, uses fewer parts, or looks better.
All that should be possible - if you have the right software. Unfortunately, there's currently no software capable of doing a physics analysis of a LEGO model.</description></item><item><title>Website</title><link>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/contributing/web/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/contributing/web/</guid><description>sdafasdasdf</description></item><item><title>Code of Conduct</title><link>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/contributing/code_of_conduct/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/contributing/code_of_conduct/</guid><description>Contributor Covenant Code of Conduct Our Pledge We as members, contributors, and leaders pledge to make participation in our community a harassment-free experience for everyone, regardless of age, body size, visible or invisible disability, ethnicity, sex characteristics, gender identity and expression, level of experience, education, socio-economic status, nationality, personal appearance, race, religion, or sexual identity and orientation.
We pledge to act and interact in ways that contribute to an open, welcoming, diverse, inclusive, and healthy community.</description></item><item><title>External documents</title><link>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/technical_info/documents/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/technical_info/documents/</guid><description>OpenGL Khronos OpenGL Wiki OpenGL 3.3 Core Specification OpenGL Tutorial (Also available as PDF) LDraw LDraw Homepage File Format Specification !COLOUR Specification Back Face Culling Specification MPD Specification</description></item><item><title>Mac OS X</title><link>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/installation/osx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/docs/installation/osx/</guid><description>currently, the only way to run BrickSim a Mac is to build it from source. A binary file will be provided as soon as I have found someone who knows how to build software on Mac OS X.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/screenshots/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bb1950328.github.io/BrickSim/screenshots/</guid><description>Here you can see how BrickSim looks and what the main features are.</description></item></channel></rss>